<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elm on Tutorials</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elm on Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Core Concepts in Elm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/elm/core_concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/elm/core_concepts/</guid>
      <description>Elm is built on a set of core concepts that make it robust and functional. Understanding these concepts is key to becoming proficient in Elm. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore some of these fundamental ideas. Types and Type Annotations&#xA;Elm is a statically typed language, meaning the type of every variable and expression is known at compile time. This feature makes your code more reliable and easier to maintain.&#xA;Basic Types&#xA;Elm has several basic types like Int, Float, String, Bool, and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elm Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/elm/elm_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/elm/elm_architecture/</guid>
      <description>Elm Architecture linkUnderstanding The Elm Architecture (TEA) is crucial for building applications in Elm. TEA is a pattern for architecting web applications. It is simple yet powerful, helping you to build well-structured and easily maintainable applications.&#xA;Components of The Elm Architecture linkTEA revolves around three main concepts: Model, Update, and View. Together, these components create a unidirectional data flow that is easy to understand and debug. Model&#xA;The model represents the state of your application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Elm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/elm/getting_started_with_elm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/elm/getting_started_with_elm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Elm linkElm is a delightful language for reliable web applications. It compiles to JavaScript, but it&amp;rsquo;s much more than just a language; it&amp;rsquo;s a framework for making web development more robust and pleasant. One of the most striking features of Elm is its emphasis on simplicity and quality tooling, making it an excellent choice for both beginners and experienced developers.&#xA;Why Elm? linkSimplicity and Safety&#xA;Elm&amp;rsquo;s syntax is clean and easy to understand, making it an ideal starting point for those new to programming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working with HTTP Requests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/elm/working_with_http_requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/elm/elm/working_with_http_requests/</guid>
      <description>Working with HTTP Requests linkElm provides a smooth way to handle HTTP requests with the Http module.&#xA;Making a GET Request&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of how to make a GET request to fetch data:&#xA;fetchDataCmd : Cmd Msg fetchDataCmd = Http.get { url = &amp;#34;https://api.example.com/data&amp;#34; , expect = Http.expectString ReceiveData } This function creates a command that, when executed, sends a GET request to the specified URL and expects a string response.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
