<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erlang on Tutorials</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/erlang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Erlang on Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/erlang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Erlang Concepts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/erlang/erlang/advanced_erlang_concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/erlang/erlang/advanced_erlang_concepts/</guid>
      <description>Advanced Erlang Concepts linkConcurrent Programming in Erlang linkErlang is renowned for its excellent support for concurrent programming, which is fundamental in building scalable and reliable applications.&#xA;Processes in Erlang&#xA;Erlang handles concurrency through lightweight processes, which are isolated and run in parallel. These processes communicate via message passing, avoiding shared state and ensuring robustness.&#xA;Message Passing&#xA;Processes exchange information using asynchronous message passing, which is a safe and efficient way to handle inter-process communication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn about Erlang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/erlang/erlang/getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/erlang/erlang/getting_started/</guid>
      <description>Brief History of Erlang linkErlang was created by Ericsson&amp;rsquo;s Computer Science Lab in 1986 for handling large-scale telecommunications projects. Its development was driven by the need for a robust system capable of managing numerous concurrent activities, with high levels of fault tolerance. Over the years, Erlang has evolved significantly and is now used in various domains, including banking, e-commerce, and instant messaging.&#xA;Key Features of Erlang linkErlang stands out due to its unique features, which include:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Applications and Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/erlang/erlang/applications_and_best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/erlang/erlang/applications_and_best_practices/</guid>
      <description>Practical Applications and Best Practices linkReal-World Applications of Erlang linkErlang&amp;rsquo;s unique features make it a preferred choice in several critical industries:&#xA;Case Studies&#xA;Notable examples include WhatsApp for instant messaging, Ericsson for telecommunications, and Klarna for online payments. These applications leverage Erlang&amp;rsquo;s ability to handle massive concurrency and maintain high availability.&#xA;Industry Use-Cases&#xA;Erlang is extensively used in sectors requiring scalable, fault-tolerant systems, such as banking, e-commerce, telecommunication, and cloud computing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
