<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ocaml on Tutorials</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/ocaml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ocaml on Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/ocaml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Concepts in OCaml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/ocaml/ocaml/advanced_ocaml_concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/ocaml/ocaml/advanced_ocaml_concepts/</guid>
      <description>Advanced OCaml Concepts linkAs we delve deeper into OCaml, we encounter advanced features that provide powerful tools for software development. These include modules, error handling, and object-oriented features.&#xA;Modules and Namespaces linkModules in OCaml are like containers for types, functions, and sub-modules, providing a way to organize and reuse code. They act as namespaces to prevent naming conflicts.&#xA;Here’s how to define a simple module:&#xA;module MathOps = struct let add a b = a &amp;#43; b let subtract a b = a - b end;; You can access module contents using the dot notation:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core Concepts in OCaml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/ocaml/ocaml/core_concepts_in_ocaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/ocaml/ocaml/core_concepts_in_ocaml/</guid>
      <description>Core Concepts in OCaml linkData Types and Variables linkOCaml supports several basic data types:&#xA;Integers: let a = 5 Floating-point numbers: let b = 5.0 Strings: let c = &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot; Booleans: let d = true Variable declaration in OCaml is immutable by default, which means once a value is assigned to a variable, it cannot be changed.&#xA;Control Structures linkOCaml includes several control structures for decision-making and looping:&#xA;If-Else Statements:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Ocaml </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/ocaml/ocaml/introduction_to_ocaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/docs/ocaml/ocaml/introduction_to_ocaml/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to OCaml linkOCaml is a multi-paradigm programming language, an extension of the Caml language, and a member of the ML (Meta Language) family. It emerged in the mid-1990s and was developed by INRIA, a French national research institution. Its design offers a functional, imperative, and object-oriented programming style.&#xA;Key Features of OCaml: link Strong static typing: Errors are caught at compile time, reducing runtime errors. Type inference: The compiler deduces types, simplifying the coding process.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
